The revolution won't be paywalled
Adam Vials Moore, November 2025
You will not be able to access
the research, brothers and sisters,
Because your library
cancelled the subscription.
You did the research
with your own hands,
You reviewed the papers for free,
You edited the journal for nothing,
And then they charged you
thousands to publish,
Millions to read it back.
This isn't a publishing model.
This is extraction.
This is capitalism
in a white coat.
The revolution won't be paywalled.
The revolution will not be brought
to you by Elsevier,
Springer, Wiley, Taylor & Francis—
The publishers who make more profit
than tech giants
While paying scholars nothing.
The revolution won't be paywalled,
brothers and sisters.
The revolution won't have
an article processing charge.
The revolution won't require
institutional access.
The revolution will be
Diamond Open Access.
scholar-governed.
The revolution will be knowledge
as a commons, not a commodity.
You cannot stay home and publish
in Nature and ignore the system.
Because the system is broken,
And your students can't afford it,
And the Global South
can't access it,
And the public can't read
the research they paid for.
The revolution will be
editorial boards walking out.
libraries cancelling big deals.
The revolution will be
scholars taking back what's ours.
The knowledge is ours.
The expertise is ours.
The legitimacy is ours.
We've been giving them away.
We can stop.
The revolution won't be paywalled.
The revolution will be open.
And it starts now.